The World to Come is a romance, drama, western film directed by Mona Fastvold.
In 1856, two women forge a close connection despite
their isolation on the American frontier.
Abigail, played by Katherine Waterston.
Dyer, played by Casey Affleck.
Tallie, played by Vanessa Kirby.
Finney, played by Christopher Abbott.
Widow Weldon's Son, played by Kim Ciobanu.
Tinker, played by Daniel Blumberg.
The World to Come is a 2020 American historical drama film directed by Mona Fastvold from a screenplay
by Ron Hansen and Jim Shepard, based on Shepard's 2017 short story of the same name.
It stars Katherine Waterston, Vanessa Kirby, Christopher Abbott, and Casey Affleck, and follows two
neighboring couples battling hardship and isolation in mid-19th-century United States.
The film had its world premiere at the 77th Venice International Film Festival on September 6,
2020, where it won the Queer Lion award for best LGBTQ-themed film at the festival.
The film was released in the United States by Bleecker Street in select theaters
on February 12, 2021, and on premium video on demand on March 2.
The film explores themes of lesbian relationship,
grim, lyrical, lesbian, intimate.
The tone is emotional.